A Register of the Papers of the Suvorovskii kadetskii korpus
Hoover Institution Archives
Suvorovskii kadetskii korpus
1899-1972
2008C87
Suvorovskiĭ kadetskiĭ korpus.
6 microfilm reels 0.9 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
These papers consist of select records of the Suvorovskii kadetskii korpus (Suvorov cadet corps), located in Moscow, whose members were active in emigration in its alumni association. The records relate to the history of the cadet corps as well as the fate of the corps' alumni in the diaspora.
Administrative Information
Access
The collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2008
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Location of Original Materials
Holy Trinity Orthodox Seminary, Jordanville, New York
Scope and Content of Collection
These papers consist of select records of the Suvorovskii kadetskii korpus (Suvorov cadet corps), located in Moscow, whose members were active in emigration in its alumni association. The records relate to the history of the cadet corps as well as the fate of the corps' alumni in the diaspora. Included among the documents are correspondence, memoirs, and photographs. Of special interest are records pertaining to the annual celebration of the corps' feast day, October 14th. The rich collection of prints, dating from 1899-1964 and totaling five hundred and sixty nine provides a rich source of information, as most prints are described in detail.
Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and the Holy Trinity Seminary. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials remain in the Holy Trinity Seminary Archives as its property. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is appended to this register. Any views, findings, conclusions or recommendations expressed in these materials do not necessarily represent those of the National Endowment for the Humanities.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into three series: Office file, Photographs, and Miscellany
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the online catalog.
Subjects
Military cadets--Russia.; Rossiiskii imperatorskii Suvorovskii kadetskii korpus.; Suvorov, Aleksandr Vasil'evich.; Vera Konstantinovna, kniazhna.; Photographs.; Diaries.
Separated Material
The periodical Suvorovtsy, published in Paris, has been separated to the periodical collection. See periodical catalog
Duplicate issues of Kadetskii golos iz provintsii have been separated to the periodical collection. See periodical catalog
Collection Contents
- Office file, 1900-1972 and undated. (Box 1)
  Announcements, brochures, clippings, correspondence, diary, memoirs, notes, postcards, printed matter, prints, reports, speeches, statutes, and student records. Arranged alphabetically by physical form
  - General, 1954-1960 and undated. (Folder 1: 1)
    Clippings, correspondence, poems
  - Announcements, 1954-1963 and undated (Folder 1: 2)
  - Chronological file, 1946-1962 and undated
    - Annual celebration of cadet corps' feast
      - 1946 (Folder 1: 3)
      - 1947 (Folder 1: 4)
      - 1948 (Folder 1: 5)
      - 1949 (Folder 1: 6)
      - 1950 (Folder 1: 7)
      - 1951 (Folder 1: 8)
      - 1952 (Folder 1: 9)
      - 1953 (Folder 1: 10)
      - 1954 (Folder 1: 11)
      - 1955 (Folder 1: 12)
      - 1956 (Folder 1: 13)
      - 1957 (Folder 1: 14)
      - 1958 (Folder 1: 15)
      - 1959 (Folder 1: 16)
      - 1960 (Box-folder 2: 1)
      - 1961 (Folder 2: 2)
      - 1962 (Folder 2: 3)
    - Correspondence, 1947-1961 and undated
      Arranged chronologically
      - General
        - 50th anniversary of cadet corps, 1949-1957 (Folder 2: 4)
        - Memorial medal, 1957 (Folder 2: 5)
      - 1947-1950 and undated (Folder 2: 6)
      - 1951-1952 (Folder 2: 7)
      - 1953-1954 (Folder 2: 8)
      - 1955 (Folder 2: 9)
      - 1956-1957 (Folder 2: 10)
      - 1958-1959 (Folder 2: 11)
      - 1960 (Folder 2: 12)
      - 1961 (Folder 2: 13)
  - Diary – Andreev, Nikolai N., 1910-1914 (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - Memoirs, 1908-1960
    - Unidentified, 1908 (Folder 3: 2)
    - Potapov, Aleksandr Nikolaevich, "Chernoviki suvorovtsa,", 1950-1960. (Folder 3: 3-6)
      Eight notebooks containing memoirs on cadet corps attendance and history of the Suvorovskii kadetskii korpus, as well as information relating to alumni
  - Notes, undated (Folder 3: 7)
  - Reports, 1971-1972 (Folder 3: 8)
  - Student records, 1910-1914 (Folder 3: 9)
  - Subject file, 1900-1961 (Box 4)
    - Delo o znameni Simbirskogo kadetskogo korpusa, 1954-1961. (Folder 4: 1-2)
      Includes clippings, correspondence, notes, prints
    - Potapov, Aleksandr Nikolaevich, 1959-1960 and undated. (Folder 4: 3)
      Postcards
    - Suvorov, Aleksandr Vasil'evich, 1900-1959 and undated. (Folder 4: 4)
      Brochures, clippings, correspondence, notes, prints
    - Vera Konstantinovna, kniazhna, 1958. (Folder 4: 5)
      Compilation of materials related to the visit of Vera Konstantinovna to festivities in Montreal, dedicated to the memory of the 100th anniversary of the birth of Grand Duke Konstantin Konstantinovich. Includes memoirs, speeches, poems, six prints
  - Statutes, 1957-1964 (Folder 4: 6)
  - Printed matter, 1900-1957
    - General, 1900-1954. (Folder 4: 7)
      Four books from the library of the cadet corps alumni association. Not filmed
    - Dobrovolets. Organ vnutrennei sviazi kadrov ROA, 1953. (Folder 4: 8)
      Printed copy
    - Dvigubskii, Sergei Grigor'evich
      - Obshchaia tetrad' (Vospominaniia suvorovtsa), 1947-1948. (Folder 4: 9)
        Signed copy, includes letter and dedication to A. N. Potapov, dated 1949
      - Prilozhenie k obshchei tetradi, 1949. (Box-folder 5: 1)
        Includes letter, dated 1956
      - Suvorov, 1944 (Folder 5: 2)
    - Informatsiia general'nogo sekretariata soiuza R.K.K., 1962. (Folder 5: 3)
      Published by Sergei G. Dvigubskii, printed copies
    - Kadetskii golos iz provintsii, 1952-1957.
      Includes prints and related correspondence
      - Nos. 1-6, 1952 (Folder 5: 4)
      - Nos. 7-12, 1953 (Folder 5: 5)
      - Nos. 13-18, 1954 (Folder 5: 6)
      - Nos. 19-24, 1955 (Folder 5: 7)
      - Nos. 25-30, 1956 (Folder 5: 8)
      - Nos. 31-36, 1957 (Folder 5: 9)
- Photographs, 1899-1962 and undated.
  Alumni and related photographs. Five hundred sixty nine prints, including cards. Arranged according to original order
  - General, 1951-1959 and undated. (Folder 5: 10)
    Six prints
  - Prikhodkin, Boris Dmitrievich, undated. (Folder 5: 11)
    One print
  - Suvorovskii kadetskii korpus
    - Alumni and related
      - One hundred seventy eight prints, including cards and student records. Majority of prints are described in detail, 1899-1916 and undated. (Folder 5: 12)
      - One hundred fifty three print and cards, described and identified, 1907-1962 and undated. (Box-folder 6: 1)
      - Two hundred thirty two prints and cards, described and identified., 1923-1957 and undated. (Folder 6: 2)
- Miscellany, 1958 and undated.
  Commemorative cards, keys, five medals, three shoulder straps. Not filmed
  - Cards, commemorative, and depicting Ravensburg, 1958 and undated (Folder 6: 3)
  - Keys of former archive storage. (Folder 6: 4)
    Not filmed
  - Collection of five medals, three shoulder straps, belonging to Lev Mikhailovich Loban, Sergei Viktorovich Nitts, Aleksei Pavlovich Pukhlovskii, and Anatolii Nikolaevich Reshko. (Folder 6: 5)